DONATO E. BORRELLO

4 Park Avenue #9B, New York, NY 10016 ⋈ venar303@gmail.com ☎ (917) 280-0069

Summary

Motivated and enthusiastic technology leader with 15 years of experience writing semicolons, leading teams and delivering products. Has repeatedly been able to dive-deep on technical problems and emerge as a thought-leader in various fields. Recognized for his ability to gather information and provide a clear vision for achieving both short and long-term goals. Able to translate needs from business to the technical side and back. Proven track-record for hiring a talented, complementary, and highly effective team.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science University of Rochester May 2012 Rochester, NY

EXPERIENCE

JW PLAYER
LEAD ENGINEER

APRIL 2016 - PRESENT NEW YORK, NY

- Hired and lead a team of 8 to be self-sufficient, guiding them to timely completion of projects.
- Iteratively delivered products, which doubled customer engagement twice in 6 months.
- Drove data architecture decisions when scaling systems to handle over 60k events/sec.
- Centralized information related to systems architecture and created the de-facto blueprint used by all members of our organization.
- Pushed a values-driven culture and empowered IC's to make trade-offs independently when appropriate.
- Performed technical comparisons and break-even analysis of technology stacks, then negotiated package pricing with cloud providers including AWS, Snowflake and ModeAnalytics.
- Revamped processes for Database Change Management and Incident Response to 50 engineers across 6 teams; decreasing service outages from 0.15% to 0.01% weekly.

JW PLAYER SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER May 2014 - April 2016 New York, NY

- Lead Engineer on implementing VPAID2 specification from IAB, which services over 250M ads/month.
- Lead Engineer on implementing HLS standard from Apple, which services over 6Bn video streams/month.
- Redesigned the javascript message bus for higher performance, shaving 20% off startup time.
- Prototyped and built a full-stack testing framework Squash to combine automated and manual tests.
- Through iterative development, Squash decreased regression testing from 4 weeks to 1 week, to 3 days.

FACTSET RESEARCH SYSTEMS SOFTWARE ENGINEER June 2012 - April 2014 New York, NY

- Performed as Technical Lead on a full stack analytics reporting application, which had the fastest rendering time among hundreds in the CoMA division of FactSet.
- Learned to maintain, extend, and love legacy codebases. Or at least love refactoring them. Never learned to love VMS.
- Created a tool *p4-compare*, which let developers compare the cyclomatic complexity of their change against what is in master.
- Worked across departments creating a new Backbone toolkit for rapidly prototyping new reports. It is currently improving productivity for teams in New York, Norwalk and London.

- Researched methods to provide economically viable real-time audio transcription for hearing-impaired internet users.
- Developed PHP-API for Amazon Mechanical Turk which allowed easier integration of external datasources and enhanced real-time processing capabilities.
- Participated in project planning, design, and development of services for gathering and retaining Amazon Mechanical Turk workers.

Freelance

CHILDHOOD - PRESENT ROCHESTER, NY

FULL STACK GAME DEVELOPER

- Created a new interface to an online game, Kings of Chaos, to enhance and improve fundamental gameplay.
- Provided real-time analytics comparing 800+ registered users over 13 years.
- Wrote bots to simulate human interaction, automating every aspect of gameplay. Required header-spoofing, captcha cracking, and basic NLP. (Don't tell the admins!)

Conferences

The Nitty Gritty of Adaptive Video Transmuxing

EmpireJS, 2016

A 30 minute presentation on strategies for efficiently transmuxing video for improving the time to first frame. The core principal is switching from batch computation to streaming. I discuss why Communicating Sequential Processes (CSP) works as a strong alternative to streams with back pressure.

PUBLICATIONS

Real time Captioning by Non-Experts

Nominated for best paper in the 25th Annual UIST Conference 2012: 23-34

Online Sequence Alignment for Real-Time Audio Transcription by Non-Experts

Published by the 26th Annual AAAI Conference 2012

OTHER CONTRIBUTIONS

- Founder of Election Reform New York a group pushing for Instant Run Off elections in NY
- Maintainer of Google's Karma repository, a javascript test runner
- Code contributor to Google's Shaka repository, a DASH video player
- Code contributor to Blender, an open-source 3D modeling engine
- Security research for KingsOfChaos.com, a text-based mmo
- Art contributor to Planeshift.it, an open-source 3D mmorpg
- Consultant for AI-Coin, a bitcoin variant which sacrifices decentralization for sub-second transactions
- Member of think-tank for MiMedia, a Brooklyn based startup for cloud storage of media

Lists

- Job Experience: Javascript, Python, C++, Java, Node, and git
- DB's in Prod: Redis, Mongo, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- Fun Stuff: Haskell, Starcraft, TypeScript, Database Design
- Not lovin' it: tabs, Flask, lag, Angular, Pager Duty
- Favorite Places: New York, New York, Puglia, Turks'n Caicos, Tamarindo, Buenos Aires,